Kristi Perez Bedford, mba

Houston, TX 77008

(713) 298-2873 • <u>kristi.perezbedford@gmail.com</u> https://www.linkedin.com/in/kristi-perez-bedford/

CUSTOMER RELATIONSHIP MANAGEMENT & BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE LEADER

Highly-motivated business professional with 10+ years of comprehensive experience in Customer Relationship Management (CRM), and traditional & digital marketing activities. Strong leader with demonstrated ability to execute strategic marketing plans that drive brand growth, revenue, and customer engagement.

Core Competencies

Salesforce • CRM Systems • Marketing Automation • Team Leadership & Training • Marketing Research & Analysis Cross-Department Collaboration • Process & Procedure Improvement • End-to-End Project Lifecycle

EXPERIENCE

11/2012- ION GEOPHYSICAL

HOUSTON, TX

Present

Director, CRM and Market Intelligence (11/2018 – Present) **Business Intelligence Manager** (11/2014 - 11/2018)

- Lead team of three in overseeing global market research & analysis and CRM strategy while setting and executing strategic roadmap for Salesforce within the company.
- Team up with global leadership to identify customer insights, industry trends, and competitor positioning.
- Spearhead end-to-end project lifecycle, including scope, budget, timeline, resources and deliverables for Salesforce, driving consensus, and liaising with business unit leaders and sales team to translate business requirements into technical solutions.
- Analyze various data sources to solve complex business questions raised by executive team and sales/marketing staff.
 - Produce visually compelling bi-annual market outlook regarding qualitative and quantitative research. Present findings to executive team to facilitate decision making regarding short- and long-term strategy.
 - O Utilize external (Rystad, Wood Mackenzie, IHS, FactSet) and internal data sources to determine upstream E&P industry trends, and seismic market size.
- Establish databases and capture market data shared across all company levels.
- Collaborate with ~20 executives and sales members to design and implement dashboards, alerts, and reports.
- Create quarterly PowerPoint presentation reporting competitor analysis to Board of Directors.
- Develop and deliver training programs to sales, operations, and marketing teams; provide one-on-one training to executive leadership as needed.
- Collaborated with marketing communication to generate marketing automation framework for customer segmentation by integrating Salesforce functionality with marketing tools.
- Streamlined and designed customer satisfaction surveys to provide valuable customer insight to business segments.
- Analyze existing processes, leveraging technological tools to drive optimization.
 - Utilized Salesforce to streamline sales reporting and develop documentation and procedures.
- Perform bi-annual employee reviews to provide regular feedback; actively seek development opportunities to support growth of individual career goals.

Product Marketing Manager (11/2012-11/2014)

- Managed enhancements, customization, and utilization of Salesforce from business unit perspective while providing market intelligence to executive and business unit leaders to facilitate critical decisions.
- Created and implemented marketing strategies and tactics to optimize equipment sales. Gathered and analyzed market intelligence, provided market forecasts, and opportunity metrics (won/lost analysis); monitored and benchmarked competitive products and capabilities.
- Liaised with sales team, Salesforce administrator, and third-party vendors to define business requirements, perform process reengineering, and test/implement solutions.

• Defined and executed integrated marketing program to relay product benefits to customers. Determined messaging for trade shows, brochures, and digital campaigns.

2/2010- **GEOKINETICS INC.** (Acquired PGS Onshore, Inc.)

HOUSTON, TX

- 11/2012 Manager, Technical Marketing
 - Spearheaded digital marketing strategy for \$549M company while serving as digital innovation advocate.
 - Saved company \$100K in implementation and configuration costs through identification and proposal of software as a service (SaaS) CRM solution.
 - Designed and deployed Salesforce to five global offices. Performed data management, testing, segmentation, analytics, training, user support, and campaign management.
 - Employed change management frameworks to support user adoption and enhance executive support.
 - Defined and aligned business processes/requirements with Salesforce, recommending process reengineering when appropriate.
 - Actively sought opportunities for optimization and efficiency, managing all system enhancements. Managed third party vendors when Visualforce was necessary for custom objects.
 - Oversaw redesign of company website on CMS platform, enabling in-house content changes and eliminating continued outsourced development costs. Utilized SEO and SEM to enhance positioning; provided web analytics utilizing Google Analytics.
 - Launched integrated email marketing initiative to reinforce Geokinetics brand and increase company technology profile.

9/2001- **PGS ONSHORE, INC.**

HOUSTON, TX

Senior Marketing Coordinator

Marketing Administrative Assistant

- Executed \$1.2M strategic marketing communications plan for onshore business unit consistent with overall strategy. Activities included managing targeted marketing campaigns, trade shows, advertising, brochures, direct mail, email marketing, and multimedia.
- Oversaw end-to-end trade shows in North America and Latin America.
- Performed graphic design work and wrote copy for marketing communication activities as needed.
- Managed end-to-end relationship with external agencies/vendors, from prospecting to executing defined creative workplan.

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

- **Product Analyst**, Qwest Communications (10/2000-7/2001)
- Regional Marketing/Promotions, 24 Hour Fitness (2/2000-10/2000)

EDUCATION

2/2010

2019 **DIGITAL CRAFTS**

Full Stack Immersive Program, Software Development

2013 TULANE UNIVERSITY

Master of Business Administration

1999 UNIVERSITY OF COLORADO, DENVER

Bachelor of Science, Business Administration

Major: Marketing

TECHNICAL

JavaScript, Node.js, Python, HTML, CSS, RESTful API, PostgreSQL, Express, Sequelize, Salesforce, Skuid, Web Content Management Systems (EPiServer, FlexWEB, SharePoint), Email Marketing (Pardot, Exact Target), Google Analytics, GetFeedback, Adobe Creative Suite (Acrobat, Photoshop InDesign, Illustrator), Microsoft Office